Concrete Designs Inc. Records, 1902-2007 (bulk 1952-2007)
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
Concrete Designs Inc. Records, 1902-2007 (bulk 1952-2007)
MS 548
Concrete Designs Inc. Records
This collection contains correspondence, office memos, financial documents, legal documents, designs, catalogs, brochures, reports, photographs, and three dimensional objects relating to Keith Martin and his business Concrete Designs Inc. Also included are materials from Keith Martin’s tenure as exploration geologist for the Hope Mining and Milling Corporation.
8 Linear Feet
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections University of Arizona PO Box 210055 Tucson, AZ 85721-0055 Phone: 520-621-6423 Fax: 520-621-9733 URL: http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/ E-Mail: LBRY-askspcoll@email.arizona.edu
Restrictions
There are no restrictions on this collection.
Historical Note
Concrete Designs Inc. was founded in Tucson, Arizona in 1958 by Keith Martin who was the company’s principle designer and president. The company specialized in architectural details, including window sills, valences, corbels, and columns in concrete with a design emphasis on Spanish / Colonial architecture. The company was sold in 1995 to Oldcastle a firm based in Ireland. By that time the company had become the largest manufacture of ornamental precast concrete in the United States.
Keith Martin earned his MA in Geology from the University of Arizona in the early 1950s. Soon thereafter he began a longtime professional relationship with the Kennecott Copper Company and Hope Mining and Milling Company working as an exploration geologist in Arizona and the Southwest for both companies. This work lead to the discovery of the Ithaca Peak copper deposit near Kingman, Arizona. Keith Martin died in February, 2008.
Arrangement
This collection is organized into seven series.
Series I: Business Records, 1974-2005
Series II: Reports, 1958-1994
Series III: Designs, 1964-1992
Series IV: Newsletters, 1988-1993
Series V: Objects, undated
Series VI: Photographs, 1966-1992
Series VII: Hope Mining and Milling Corporation Materials, 1952-1978
Scope and Content Note
This collection contains materials collected by Keith Martin who founded Concrete Designs Inc. in 1958 and also served as its president and principle designer. The collection has seven series. The first series contains business records of Concrete Designs Inc. and consists of office memos, financial documents, legal documents, designs, catalogs, brochures, reports, and photographs that document products manufactured by Concrete Designs Inc. as well as commissioned projects. The second series contains financial reports, financial statements, price lists, stock transfer information, and materials documenting the sale of the company to Irish firm Oldcastle. The third series contains designs of products and commissioned projects. The fourth series contains newsletters produced by the company which were intended for internal circulation. The fifth series contains three dimensional objects and consists of an ornamental design made from foam and a company T-shirt. The sixth series contains black and white prints, color prints, negatives, and slides of products and worksite. The seventh series contains Hope Mining and Milling Corporation materials that were collected by Keith Martin during his tenure working for the company as an exploration geologist in Arizona and the Southwest. This series contains correspondence, office memos, meeting minutes, topographic maps, and business arrangements with other mining companies regarding specific mining sites in southern Arizona.
Access Terms
Decoration and ornament, Architectural - United States.
Architecture.
Architecture - Accounting.
Mining Corporations - United States.
Mining Leases - Arizona.
Mineral industries - Arizona - Finances - Sources.
Container List
- Series 1: Business Records, 1972-2007
  Series is arranged chronologically and contains materials documenting daily business operations of Concrete Designs Inc. including office memos, financial documents, legal documents, designs, catalogs, brochures, reports, and photographs.
  - Tooling Schedules, 1972-1982 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Concrete Designs Inc. History, 1973-2000 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Business Records (1 of 3), 1974-1979 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Business Records (2 of 3), 1974-1979 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Business Records (3 of 3), 1974-1979 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Concrete Designs Inc. History, 1979-1996 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Business Records, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Concrete Designs Inc. History, 1982-1987 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Business Records, 1982-1984 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Business Records, 1985-1986 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Don Lobiondo Claim, 1985-1995 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Management Priorities, 1985-1987 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Project Pending List, 1985-1988 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Ibiss West Sales Documents, 1986-1987 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Business Records (1 of 3), 1987 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Business Records (2 of 3), 1987 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Business Records (3 of 3), 1987 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Criticisms and Other Notes, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Sale and Related Data, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Stock Evaluations and Business Broker Solicitations, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Business Records (1 of 2), 1988 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Business Records (2 of 2), 1988 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Business Records (1 of 3), 1989 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Business Records (2 of 3), 1989 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Business Records (3 of 3), 1989 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Business Records (1 of 2), 1990 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Business Records (2 of 2), 1990 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Business Records (1 of 2), 1991 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Business Records (2 of 2), 1991 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Tempe Lands, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Business Records (1 of 3), 1992 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Business Records (2 of 3), 1992 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Business Records (3 of 3), 1992 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Business Records (1 of 4), 1993 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Business Records (2 of 4), 1993 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Business Records (3 of 4), 1993 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Business Records (4 of 4), 1993 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Concrete Designs Inc. Reorganization, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Oldcastle Counter Proposal, 1993-1994 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Business Records (1 of 3), 1994 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Business Records (2 of 3), 1994 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Business Records (3 of 3), 1994 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Dave Sanz Gift, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Business Records (1 of 2), 1995 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Business Records (2 of 2), 1995 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Larson Purchase Proposal, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Business Records (1 of 6), 1996 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Business Records (2 of 6), 1996 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Business Records (3 of 6), 1996 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Business Records (4 of 6), 1996 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Business Records (5 of 6), 1996 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Business Records (6 of 6), 1996 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Concrete Designs Inc. Oldcastle Sale, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Business Records, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Business Records, 1998 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Business Records, 1999 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Business Records, 2000-2007 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Series 2: Reports, 1958-1994
  Series is arranged alphabetically by report type and then chronologically. It contains financial reports, financial statements, price lists, stock transfer information, and materials documenting the sale of the company to Irish firm Oldcastle.
  - Financial Reports (1 of 3), 1987-1988 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Financial Reports (2 of 3), 1987-1988 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Financial Reports (3 of 3), 1987-1988 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Financial Statements, 1958-1966 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Financial Statements, 1976-1977 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Financial Statements, 1978-1981 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Financial Statements, 1981-1984 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Financial Statements, 1984-1987 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Financial Statements, 1988-1991 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Financial Statements, 1991-1993 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Financial Statements, 1993-1994 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Financial Statements, 2002, 2005 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Oldcastle Sale Data (1 of 2), 1970-1994 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Oldcastle Sale Data (2 of 2), 1970-1994 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Price List, 1985-1986 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Price List, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Stock Transfer (1 of 2), 1986-1991 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Stock Transfer (2 of 2), 1986-1991 (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Series 3: Designs, 1964-1992
  Series is arranged alphabetically by design type and then chronologically. It contains correspondence, sketches, research, product lists, and plans for products produced for commercial sale by Concrete Designs Inc as well as commissioned projects. This series also contains a folder of general research materials.
  - Administration Building, 1991-1993 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Administration Building Architecturals, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Administration Building Site Improve, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Bars, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Clerestory, 1990-1991 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Columns, 1983-1993 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Columns, 1997-1998 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Fireplaces, 1974-1993 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Fireplaces Three Ring Binder, 1984-1986 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Fireplaces, Hearths, Mantels, 1973-1982 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Fireplaces, Keith Martin Studies, 1976, undated (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Floors, Miscellaneous Reference Materials, 1964-1975 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Lamps, 1989-1999 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Main Entry, 1990-1992 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Moldings, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Ornament, 1972-1979 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Pavers, 1971-1982 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Plasters, 1990-1991 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Product Catalogs, undated (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Product List, 1976-1982 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Product List, 1979-1983 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Profiles, 1991-1992 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Reception and Sales Desks, undated (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Research materials, 1968-2005 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Sales Book (1 of 3), 1971-1984 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Sales Book (2 of 3), 1971-1984 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Sales Book (3 of 3), 1971-1984 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - South Elevations, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - 13 Tables, Desks, Cabinets, 1993-1996 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Unidentified Designs, 1990-1993 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Walk in Sales Desk, 1991-1992 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - West End, 1990-1991 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Windows, 1972-1978 (Box 6, Folder 17)
- Series 4: Newsletters, 1988-1993
  This series is arranged chronologically. It contains copies of the Something Concrete and CDI News Newsletters, which were publications produced by Concrete Designs Inc. intended for internal use.
  - Something Concrete, 1988-1991 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - CDI News title>, 1991-1993 (Box 6, Folder 19)
- Series 5: Objects, undated
  This series contains two three dimensional objects. The first object is an ornament design made from foam. The second is a Concrete Designs Inc. promotional T shirt.
  - Ornament Design, undated (Box 7)
  - Concrete Designs Inc. T Shirt, undated (Box 7)
- Series 6: Photographs, 1966-1992
  This series contains black and white and color prints, negatives and slides. The materials document the Concrete Designs Inc. warehouse, products produced by the company, and various worksites and projects. The materials are unidentified and mostly undated.
  - Photographs (1 of 2), 1966-1992 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Photographs (2 of 2), 1966-1992 (Box 8, Folder 2)
- Series 7: Hope Mining and Milling Corporation Materials, 1952-1978
  This series is arranged chronologically. It contains materials documenting Keith Martin's tenue as exploration geologist in Arizona and the Southwest for the Hope Mining and Milling Corporation. Series contains correspondence, lease agreements, topographic maps, etc. of the Turquoise Mining District of Southern Arizona.
  - Mining Claim Plats, 1902-1908 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Arizona Topographic Maps, 1948-1958 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1952-1953 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Bear Creek Mining Company, 1958-1968 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1958-1962 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Keith Martin Summary of Expenses, 1961-1962 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Winchester Mining Claim, 1961-1981 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Shalom Makalla Lease Agreement, 1962 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Shalom Makalla Lease Agreement, 1962 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Direct Minerals Inc., 1963 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Interstate Cement CU Shipments, 1963-1966 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Sam Makalla Progress Reports, 1963 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Minutes of Special Meeting of the Board of Directors, 1963 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, 1964-1971 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Data Agreements, 1964-1971 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Miscellaneous Reports, 1966-1972 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Turquoise Mining District, 1966 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Arivaca Mining Company Lease, 1969 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Aztec Mining Company Agreements, 1969-1970 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Aztec Mining Company Smelter Returns, 1969-1970 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - No Lien Notices, 1969 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Courtland, Arizona Mining Properties, 1972, undated (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - California Exploration Company, 1974 (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Superior Oil, 1975, June (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Winchester Mine Trip, 1978 (Box 8, Folder 26)